const qnsObj = {
    basico: {
        lectura1:[
            {
                num      : 1,
                question : 'What is one benefit of using public transport?',
                options  : ['It increases traffic congestion.',
                            'It saves money on fuel and maintenance.',
                            'It contributes to air pollution.'],
                answer   : "It saves money on fuel and maintenance."
            },
            {
                num      : 2,
                question : 'How does public transport affect traffic congestion?',
                options  : ['It increases congestion.',
                            'It reduces congestion.',
                            'It has no impact on congestion.'],
                answer   : "It reduces congestion."
            },
            {
                num      : 3,
                question : 'Why is public transport considered environmentally friendly?',
                options  : ['It produces more emissions than cars.',
                            'It contributes to air pollution.',
                            'It produces fewer emissions per passenger than cars.'],
                answer   : "It produces fewer emissions per passenger than cars."
            },
            {
                num      : 4,
                question : 'What is a common challenge associated with public transport?',
                options  : ['Reliability of schedules.',
                            'High cost compared to personal vehicles.',
                            'Lack of convenience.'],
                answer   : "Reliability of schedules."
            },
            {
                num      : 5,
                question : 'Why might some areas have limited public transport options?',
                options  : ['To increase traffic congestion.',
                            'To save money on maintenance.',
                            'Due to infrastructure limitations.'],
                answer   : "Due to infrastructure limitations."
            },
            {
                num      : 6,
                question : 'What is the main topic of this reading?',
                options  : ['The benefits of owning a personal vehicle.',
                            'The challenges of using public transport.',
                            'Public transport and its advantages.'],
                answer   : "Public transport and its advantages."
            },
        ],
        lectura2:[
            {
                num      : 1,
                question : 'How long have Alice and the narrator been friends?',
                options  : ['Since high school',
                            'Since kindergarten',
                            'Since college'],
                answer   : "Since kindergarten"
            },
            {
                num      : 2,
                question : "What do Alice and the narrator have in common?",
                options  : ["They both enjoy cooking.",
                            "They both enjoy mystery novels.",
                            "They both like to travel."],
                answer   : "They both enjoy mystery novels."
            },
            {
                num      : 3,
                question : "What is one thing the narrator values the most about their friendship with Alice?",
                options  : ["Their shared interest in sports.",
                            "Alice's great sense of humor.",
                            "Their love for shopping."],
                answer   : "Alice's great sense of humor."
            },
            {
                num      : 4,
                question : "How does Alice support the narrator when they have a problem?",
                options  : ["She ignores them.",
                            "She listens and offers advice.",
                            "She criticizes them."],
                answer   : "She listens and offers advice."
            },
            {
                num      : 5,
                question : "What is the main topic of the reading?",
                options  : ["A trip to a foreign country.",
                            "The narrator's family.",
                            "My best friend Alice."],
                answer   : "My best friend Alice."
            },
            {
                num      : 6,
                question : "What do the narrator and Alice often do together?",
                options  : ["Play video games.",
                            "Go to the Gym.",
                            "Discuss books and watch movies."],
                answer   : "Discuss books and watch movies."
            },
        ],
        lectura3:[
            {
                num      : 1,
                question : "How would you describe someone who is not very tall?",
                options  : ["Short",
                            "Tall",
                            "Average height"],
                answer   : "Short"
            },
            {
                num      : 2,
                question : "What do you call someone with a thin body type?",
                options  : ["Overweight",
                            "Slim",
                            "Athletic"],
                answer   : "Slim"
            },
            {
                num      : 3,
                question : "Which phrase describes hair that is neither long nor short?",
                options  : ["Long",
                            "Short",
                            "Average length"],
                answer   : "Average length"
            },
            {
                num      : 4,
                question : "What is a common way to describe someone's eye color?",
                options  : ["Brown",
                            "Tall",
                            "Overweight"],
                answer   : "Brown"
            },
            {
                num      : 5,
                question : "What should you mention if someone is wearing glasses?",
                options  : ["Their favorite color",
                            "Their height",
                            "Their eyewear"],
                answer   : "Their eyewear"
            },
            {
                num      : 6,
                question : "What might you mention if someone has a tattoo on their arm?",
                options  : ["Their favorite book",
                            "Their favorite food",
                            "Their tattoo"],
                answer   : "Their tattoo"
            },
        ]
    },
    


    intermedio: {
        lectura1:[
            {
                num      : 1,
                question : 'What is adoption?',
                options  : ['A process where children become biologically related to their new parents.',
                            'A legal process where individuals or couples become the parents of a child not biologically theirs.',
                            'A process of giving up parental rights.'],
                answer   : "A legal process where individuals or couples become the parents of a child not biologically theirs."
            },
            {
                num      : 2,
                question : 'What type of adoption involves ongoing contact between adoptive and birth parents?',
                options  : ['Open adoption',
                            'Closed adoption',
                            'International adoption'],
                answer   : "Open adoption"
            },
            {
                num      : 3,
                question : 'What is a challenge some adopted children may face?',
                options  : ['Difficulty in school',
                            'Identity issues or a desire to find their birth parents',
                            'Financial problems'],
                answer   : "Identity issues or a desire to find their birth parents"
            },
            {
                num      : 4,
                question : 'What is the primary benefit of adoption for adoptive parents?',
                options  : ['Financial support',
                            'Joy of parenthood and satisfaction of providing a loving home',
                            'Recognition in the community'],
                answer   : "Joy of parenthood and satisfaction of providing a loving home"
            },
            {
                num      : 5,
                question : 'What can be emotionally challenging about the adoption process?',
                options  : ['The cost of adoption',
                            'Wating for the right match and navigating legal procedures',
                            'Finding a suitable adoption agency'],
                answer   : "Wating for the right match and navigating legal procedures"
            },
            {
                num      : 6,
                question : 'What is the significance of background checks and home studies in the adoption process?',
                options  : ["They determine the child's elegibility for adoption.",
                            'They ensure prospective adoptive parents can provide a safe and supportive environment for a child.',
                            'They speed up the adoption process.'],
                answer   : "They ensure prospective adoptive parents can provide a safe and supportive environment for a child."
            },
            {
                num      : 7,
                question : 'How does international adoption differ from other types of adoption?',
                options  : ["It involves adopting a child from a different country.",
                            'It is only available to celebrities.',
                            "It excludes contact with the child's birth parents."],
                answer   : "It involves adopting a child from a different country."
            },
            {
                num      : 8,
                question : 'Why is adoption considered a mutually beneficial arrangement?',
                options  : ["Because it doesn't require any effort from adoptive parents.",
                            'Because it provides a loving home for children and fulfills the dreams of prospective parents.',
                            "Because it's a way for children to make money."],
                answer   : "Because it provides a loving home for children and fulfills the dreams of prospective parents."
            },
            {
                num      : 9,
                question : 'What is one potential challenge mentioned for adoptive parents?',
                options  : ["Difficulty in bonding with the adopted child.",
                            "The stress of the legal process.",
                            "The lack of support from the adoption agency."],
                answer   : "The stress of the legal process."
            },
            {
                num      : 10,
                question : "What is the primary aim of adoption, as stated in the text?",
                options  : ["To find children a loving family.",
                            "To create biologically related families.",
                            "To separate children from their birth parents."],
                answer   : "To find children a loving family."
            },
        ],
        lectura2:[
            {
                num      : 1,
                question : "How does Sarah approach giving advice?",
                options  : ["She offers advice without careful evaluation.",
                            "She evaluates situations methodically and offers thoughtful suggestions.",
                            "She gives emotional support without offering practical solutions."],
                answer   : "She evaluates situations methodically and offers thoughtful suggestions."
            },
            {
                num      : 2,
                question : "What makes Mark's situation complex for Sarah to advise on?",
                options  : ["Mark's problem is simple and straightforward.",
                            "Mark's issue is emotional, which might not align with Sarah's logical advice style.",
                            "Sarah is not friends with Mark."],
                answer   : "Mark's issue is emotional, which might not align with Sarah's logical advice style."
            },
            {
                num      : 3,
                question : "What is Mark primarily seeking from Sarah?",
                options  : ["Practical solutions to this problem.",
                            "Emotional support to cope with a breakup.",
                            "Financial assistance."],
                answer   : "Emotional support to cope with a breakup."
            },
            {
                num      : 4,
                question : "Why is Sarah hesistant about providing emotional support to Mark?",
                options  : ["She doesn't care about her friend's emotional needs.",
                            "She fears it might deviate from her usual advice-giving style.",
                            "She believes emotional support is more important than logical solutions."],
                answer   : "She fears it might deviate from her usual advice-giving style."
            },
            {
                num      : 5,
                question : "What is the key dilemma Sarah faces in this situation?",
                options  : ["Whether or not to distance herself from Mark.",
                            "Whether to prioritize logical solutions or emotional support for her friend.",
                            "Whether to avoid giving any advice to Mark."],
                answer   : "Whether to prioritize logical solutions or emotional support for her friend."
            },
            {
                num      : 6,
                question : "What kind of thinker is Sarah when it comes to giving advice?",
                options  : ["Impulsive and unthoughtful",
                            "Methodical and thoughtful",
                            "Emotional and unpredictable"],
                answer   : "Methodical and thoughtful"
            },
            {
                num      : 7,
                question : "What is Mark's primary emotional challenge in the reading?",
                options  : ["Coping with a medical emergency",
                            "Dealing with a breakup",
                            "Finding a new job"],
                answer   : "Dealing with a breakup"
            },
            {
                num      : 8,
                question : "Why does Sarah's approach to advising Mark raise a dilemma?",
                options  : ["Mark doesn't want advice.",
                            "Mark's situation is too simple.",
                            "The emotional nature of Mark's problem may clash wit Sarah's usual advice style."],
                answer   : "The emotional nature of Mark's problem may clash wit Sarah's usual advice style."
            },
            {
                num      : 9,
                question : "What does Sarah worry about when it comes to providing emotional support?",
                options  : ["That Mark won't appreciate it.",
                            "That it might deviate from her typical advice style.",
                            "That emotional support is never necessary."],
                answer   : "That it might deviate from her typical advice style."
            },
            {
                num      : 10,
                question : "What are two key aspects Sarah considers when deciding how to advise Mark?",
                options  : ["Emotional pain and physical therapy.",
                            "Rational thinking and adapting to emotional needs.",
                            "Financial assistance and practical solutions."],
                answer   : "Rational thinking and adapting to emotional needs."
            },
        ],
        lectura3:[
            {
                num      : 1,
                question : "What is one benefit of having a pet?",
                options  : ["They require no effort.",
                            "They can reduce stress.",
                            "They make you lonely."],
                answer   : "They can reduce stress."
            },
            {
                num      : 2,
                question : "What is a drawback of owning a pet?",
                options  : ["They never require healthcare.",
                            "They can be expensive and time-consuming.",
                            "They are excellent teachers."],
                answer   : "They can be expensive and time-consuming."
            },
            {
                num      : 3,
                question : "How can pets teach responsibility?",
                options  : ["By being self-sufficent.",
                            "By instilling a sense of accountability.",
                            "By demanding constant care."],
                answer   : "By instilling a sense of accountability."
            },
            {
                num      : 4,
                question : "Which factor can affect the decision to have a pet?",
                options  : ["Personal preferences and circumstances.",
                            "The popularity of the pet.",
                            "The pet's age."],
                answer   : "Personal preferences and circumstances."
            },
            {
                num      : 5,
                question : "What is a significant role that pets play in human lives?",
                options  : ["They are known for their selfishness.",
                            "They offer companionship and loyalty.",
                            "They make people anxious."],
                answer   : "They offer companionship and loyalty."
            },
            {
                num      : 6,
                question : "What is the main drawback of owning a pet mentioned in the reading?",
                options  : ["They require minimal effort.",
                            "They are excellent stress relievers.",
                            "They come with responsibilities."],
                answer   : "They come with responsibilities."
            },
            {
                num      : 7,
                question : "What can some pets help reduce?",
                options  : ["Blood pressure.",
                            "Responsibility.",
                            "Loneliness."],
                answer   : "Blood pressure."
            },
            {
                num      : 8,
                question : "What can owning a pet instill in children?",
                options  : ["A sense of boredom.",
                            "A sense of accountability and empathy.",
                            "A desire to travel frequently."],
                answer   : "A sense of accountability and empathy."
            },
            {
                num      : 9,
                question : "Why might some people prefer not to have pets?",
                options  : ["Because pets are never costly.",
                            "Because they prefer routine.",
                            "Because they want more freedom to travel."],
                answer   : "Because they want more freedom to travel."
            },
            {
                num      : 10,
                question : "What should you consider when deciding to have a pet?",
                options  : ["The pet's popularity.",
                            "Your lifestyle, personal preferences, and circumstances.",
                            "The pet's size."],
                answer   : "Your lifestyle, personal preferences, and circumstances."
            },
        ]
    },


    avanzado : {
        lectura1:[
            {
                num      : 1,
                question : "What is the main focus of the reading?",
                options  : ["The intelligence of elephants.",
                            "The emotional lives of animals.",
                            "The social complexity of primates."],
                answer   : "The emotional lives of animals."
            },
            {
                num      : 2,
                question : "According to the text, which animal exhibits mourning rituals similar to humans?",
                options  : ["Dogs.",
                            "Elephants.",
                            "Birds."],
                answer   : "Elephants."
            },
            {
                num      : 3,
                question : "How do scientists study the emotional lives of primates, according to the reading?",
                options  : ["By analyzing their fur patterns.",
                            "By studying their sleep patterns.",
                            "By observing facial expressions and vocalizations."],
                answer   : "By observing facial expressions and vocalizations."
            },
            {
                num      : 4,
                question : "What surprising revelation does the text make about birds and fish?",
                options  : ["They lack emotional complexity.",
                            "They exhibit emotional behaviors.",
                            "They are indifferent to social bonds."],
                answer   : "They exhibit emotional behaviors."
            },
            {
                num      : 5,
                question : "Which domesticated animals are specifically mentioned for their emotional intelligence?",
                options  : ["Cats and dogs.",
                            "Birds and fish.",
                            "Elephants and primates."],
                answer   : "Cats and dogs."
            },
            {
                num      : 6,
                question : "What is the primary argument of those who criticize the attribution of human-like emotions to animals?",
                options  : ["Animals lack any form of emotion.",
                            "It is an anthropomorphic interpretation.",
                            "Human emotions are identical to animal emotions."],
                answer   : "It is an anthropomorphic interpretation."
            },
        ],
        lectura2:[
            {
                num      : 1,
                question : "What has been a significant factor in Spain's economic recovery according to the reading?",
                options  : ["Strict labor regulations",
                            "Technological stagnation",
                            "Comprehensive economic reforms",
                            "Reduced competitiveness"],
                answer   : "Comprehensive economic reforms"
            },
            {
                num      : 2,
                question : "Which industry has exhibited remarkable resilience, contributing to job market recovery?",
                options  : ["Agriculture",
                            "Tourism",
                            "Mining",
                            "Textiles"],
                answer   : "Tourism"
            },
            {
                num      : 3,
                question : "How has the digital revolution impacted Spain's job market?",
                options  : ["It led to a decline in job opportunities",
                            "It only affected the technology sector",
                            "It transformed traditional industries and created new opportunities",
                            "It had no impact on the job market"],
                answer   : "It transformed traditional industries and created new opportunities"
            },
            {
                num      : 4,
                question : "What is mentioned as a challenge to Spain's job market recovery in the reading?",
                options  : ["Increased exports",
                            "Youth unemployment",
                            "Global economic growth",
                            "Regional collaborations"],
                answer   : "Youth unemployment"
            },
            {
                num      : 5,
                question : "What is emphasized as imperative for Spain's sustained growth and prosperity?",
                options  : ["Strict adherence to existing labor laws",
                            "Ignoring global economic dynamics",
                            "Addressing remaining challenges and staying attuned to global economic trends",
                            "Isolating the economy from international trade"],
                answer   : "Addressing remaining challenges and staying attuned to global economic trends"
            },
            {
                num      : 6,
                question : "Which aspect of Spain's job market does the reading highlight as being positively influenced by adaptability?",
                options  : ["Labor market regulations",
                            "Technological advancements",
                            "Regional disparities",
                            "Geopolitical uncertainties"],
                answer   : "Labor market regulations"
            },
            {
                num      : 7,
                question : "What role does the tourism sector play in Spain's job market recovery?",
                options  : ["It has no impact on job creation",
                            "It negatively affects other industries",
                            "It leads to a decline in hospitality jobs",
                            "It contributes significantly to job creation"],
                answer   : "It contributes significantly to job creation"
            },
            {
                num      : 8,
                question : "How does the digital economy impact traditional sectors beyond technology?",
                options  : ["It has no impact on traditional sectors",
                            "It leads to the decline of traditional industries",
                            "It creates job opportunities in complementary sectors",
                            "It isolates traditional sectors from the job market"],
                answer   : "It creates job opportunities in complementary sectors"
            },
            {
                num      : 9,
                question : "What is identified as a potential risk to Spain's economic gains in the reading?",
                options  : ["Regional collaborations",
                            "Increased exports",
                            "Geopolitical uncertainties",
                            "Youth unemployment"],
                answer   : "Geopolitical uncertainties"
            },
            {
                num      : 10,
                question : "What is the main message of the reading regarding Spain's economic journey?",
                options  : ["Spain's economic growth is isolated from global trends",
                            "Comprehensive economic reforms have hindered job creation",
                            "Resilience in key sectors and global adaptability contribute to job market revival",
                            "Spain's job market recovery is solely dependent on regional factors"],
                answer   : "Resilience in key sectors and global adaptability contribute to job market revival"
            },
        ],
        lectura3:[
            {
                num      : 1,
                question : "What is the primary focus of the passage?",
                options  : ["The challenges of implementing AI in healthcare",
                            "The intersection of AI and healthcare advancements",
                            "The limitations of machine learning algorithms"],
                answer   : "The intersection of AI and healthcare advancements"
            },
            {
                num      : 2,
                question : "In which area has AI made significant strides according to the passage?",
                options  : ["Dietary planning",
                            "Diagnostic accuracy",
                            "Fitness monitoring"],
                answer   : "Diagnostic accuracy"
            },
            {
                num      : 3,
                question : "What is one benefit of using AI in diagnostic processes mentioned in the passage?",
                options  : ["Delaying the diagnostic process",
                            "Reducing the precision of medical images",
                            "Expediting the diagnostic process"],
                answer   : "Expediting the diagnostic process"
            },
            {
                num      : 4,
                question : "How does AI contribute to preventive care, as per the passage?",
                options  : ["By ignoring patient data",
                            "Through reactive interventions",
                            "By identifying high-risk individuals"],
                answer   : "By identifying high-risk individuals"
            },
            {
                num      : 5,
                question : "What does the passage suggest about the impact of AI on healthcare costs?",
                options  : ["It has no impact",
                            "It may increase costs",
                            "It has the potential to reduce costs"],
                answer   : "It has the potential to reduce costs"
            },
            {
                num      : 6,
                question : "What is precision medicine, as mentioned in the passage?",
                options  : ["A type of surgery",
                            "Tailoring therapies based on individual characteristics",
                            "A new diagnostic tool"],
                answer   : "Tailoring therapies based on individual characteristics"
            },
            {
                num      : 7,
                question : "What are some challenges mentioned in the passage regarding AI in healthcare?",
                options  : ["The need for faster diagnostics",
                            "Data privacy, algorithmic bias, and regulatory considerations",
                            "Lack of technological advancements"],
                answer   : "Data privacy, algorithmic bias, and regulatory considerations"
            },
            {
                num      : 8,
                question : "Why is proactive care considered advantageous, according to the passage?",
                options  : ["It is less effective than reactive care",
                            "It reduces healthcare costs",
                            "It leads to delayed interventions"],
                answer   : "It reduces healthcare costs"
            },
            {
                num      : 9,
                question : "What, according to the passage, is crucial for responsible use of AI in healthcare?",
                options  : ["Ignoring ethical considerations",
                            "Rapid deployment of AI technologies",
                            "Striking a balance between innovation and ethical considerations"],
                answer   : "Striking a balance between innovation and ethical considerations"
            },
            {
                num      : 10,
                question : "In conclusion, what is the overall impact of AI in healthcare, as per the passage?",
                options  : ["Limited improvement in patient outcomes",
                            "Unprecedented opportunities for improved diagnostics and personalized treatment",
                            "No impact on the medical landscape"],
                answer   : "Unprecedented opportunities for improved diagnostics and personalized treatment"
            },
        ]
    }










}
